hey guys bre and here this is going to
be a video on how to improve your
stretching so I've got three tips for
you all right the first tip is to uh to
incorporate 3D stretching so here's what
I mean by this I'm going to put my leg
up on here okay say I'm doing a
hamstring stretch well if I just lean in
this way I'm just kind of stretching
from one dimension but I can EX
externally rotate my
hip and then I get a stretch more on the
medial
hamstrings okay and then I can also
internally rotate the
hamstrings and get more of a stretch on
the lateral
hamstrings so you can do this with a lot
of different uh stretches um you can you
know rotate so you get rotate the joints
so you get 3D stretching involved this
is just one of them again turning the
foot inwards will stretch more of the
lateral hamstrings turning the foot
outwards will stretch more of the medial
most people their lateral hamstrings are
more tight um the next tip is to uh make
make stretches functional for what
you're trying to improve so like let's
say I want to improve my ankle doors
flexion Mobility well there's a lot of
different you know you can stretch your
calves but people don't the the part at
which people when they squat down they
have problems like right in here when
they're down deep so get down deep in a
squat so watch me I'll sink down deep
and now I'm going to try to stretch I'm
going to try and get maximum dorsa
flexion here so I will just put my hands
on the ground so I'm in a squat position
I turn put my hands down and just going
to lean my body forward like that and
I'm going to lean shift to that way go
back now I'm going to focus on this
leg and again I'll do kind of 3D
stretching I will go out kind of where I
have some Varys here and go straight out
over the toe and maybe even go inwards a
little bit I don't like going into kind
of like um foot pronation and vus
collapse here but I do like kind of
getting some different angles straight
over the foot and kind of out more and
again I'm trying to just get as much
stretch right in here as possible and
shift back to this leg now people who
can't squat deep might find this
problematic but the point is this is
going to improve my ankle dorsal flexion
specific to a squat cuz I'm in a squat
position I'm deep down in here okay so
you can to do the same thing if you're
you know trying to improve your you know
your hamstring flexibility for
deadlifting get in a deadlift position
and get that hamstring stretch you know
make it specific to the exercise that
you're trying to improve your Mobility
for and the third tip is to use the
pelvis to improve the stretch use the
pelvis to to torque to put more torque
on on the stretch so let me show you
what this
means let's say I put my foot up here
okay I sink in and I'm I'm getting a
hamstring stretch right now this is
pretty good now watch this I'm going to
anterior tilt see
this so I'm going to use my pelvis
rather than just leaning in more I'm
going to use my pelvis I'm going to get
good posture here so my chest is up and
then into your tilt so using the pelvis
to increase the stretch on the
hamstrings so my pelvis here is pulling
this way stretching the hamstrings if I
want to do that on the flip side I can
get into a like a Bulgarian SP what I
can sink down and then now I'm
stretching my rectus florus I like doing
this stretch over a curved surface cuz
your it matches the Contour of you know
the crooks of your your front of your
ankle joint there and I'm going to sink
down okay and now from here I'm going to
actually post your to so watch this I
squeeze my glute and that really uh not
just squeezing the glute but can you see
how I'm poster tilting here
like that and it increases the stretch
here on my rectus Fus and in my
experience um more people have tight
rectus femoris than their their ilio
Solas so it's a very important muscle to
stretch so um again incorporate 3D
stretching stretch in functional
positions to improve what you're what
you're trying to gain Mobility for and
use the pelvis to increase the
effectivess of this stretch thanks for
watching